{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "L10", "optb": "K15", "optc": "I15", "optd": "K8", "ans": "D", "explanation": "How the number is obtained?\n2 + 4 = 6\n5 + 9 = 14\nSimilarly,\n3 + 5 = 8\nTherefore, the answer is K8."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "1", "optb": "4", "optc": "3", "optd": "6", "ans": "D", "explanation": "(5 + 4 + 7)/2 = 8\n(6 + 9 + 5)/2 = 10\n(3 + 7 + 2)/2 = 6."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "18", "optb": "12", "optc": "9", "optd": "6", "ans": "C", "explanation": "(12 + 18 + 30)/10 = 6\n(16 + 24 + 40)/10 = 8\nSimilarly, (45 + 18 + 27)/10 = 9."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "25", "optb": "37", "optc": "41", "optd": "47", "ans": "C", "explanation": "(5 x 3) + 4 = 19\nand (6 x 4) + 5 = 29\nTherefore, (7 x 5) + 6 = 41"}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "45", "optb": "41", "optc": "32", "optd": "40", "ans": "A", "explanation": "(15 x 2 - 3) = 27,\n(31 x 2 - 6) = 56\nand (45 x 2 - 9) = 81"}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "115", "optb": "130", "optc": "135", "optd": "140", "ans": "B", "explanation": "(5 x 6 x 8) + (7 x 4 x 9) = 492\nand (7 x 5 x 4) + (6 x 8 x 9) = 572\nTherefore (4 x 3 x 5) + (7 x 2 x 5) = 130."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "92", "optb": "72", "optc": "62", "optd": "99", "ans": "D", "explanation": "21 + 31 = 52\nand 39 + 46 = 85\nTherefore, 16 + 83 = 99."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "2", "optb": "3", "optc": "4", "optd": "5", "ans": "B", "explanation": "(18 x 12)/3 = 72\nand (32 x 16)/4 = 128\nTherefore, (24 x 14)/? = 112\n(336/?) = 112\n? = (336/112)\n? = 3."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "36", "optb": "48", "optc": "38", "optd": "30", "ans": "C", "explanation": "(0 + 2 + 6 + 4) - 2 = 10\nand (6 + 2 + 10 + 8) - 2 = 24\nTherefore, (4 + 14 + 12 + 10) - 2 = 38."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "41", "optb": "64", "optc": "35", "optd": "61", "ans": "B", "explanation": "(1)3 = 1, (2)3 = 8, (3)3 = 27\nTherefore, (4)3 = 64."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "13", "optb": "14", "optc": "12", "optd": "15", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Sum of numbers in lower half of the circle = 11 + 9 + 3 + 7 = 30\nSum of numbers in upper half of the circle = ? + 4 + 5 + 6 = ? + 15\nUpper half = Lower half\n30 = ? + 15 \n? = 30 - 15\n? = 15.\nThrefore, 15 is the answer."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "262", "optb": "622", "optc": "631", "optd": "824", "ans": "B", "explanation": "915 - 364 = 551\nand 789 - 543 = 246\nSimilarly, 863 - 241 = 622."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "45", "optb": "29", "optc": "39", "optd": "37", "ans": "C", "explanation": ""}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "184", "optb": "210", "optc": "241", "optd": "425", "ans": "A", "explanation": "(12)2 - (8)2 = 80\nand (16)2 - (7)2 = 207\nTherefore (25)2 - (21)2 = 184."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "25", "optb": "59", "optc": "48", "optd": "73", "ans": "D", "explanation": "(2)3 + (1)3 + (3)3 = 36\nand (0)3 + (4)3 + (3)3 = 91\nTherefore, (4)3 + (2)3 + (1)3 = 73."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "0", "optb": "2", "optc": "11", "optd": "12", "ans": "C", "explanation": "(6 + 5) - (7 + 4) = 0\nand (7 + 6) - (8 + 4) = 1\nTherefore (11 + 2) - (2 + 0) = 11."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "64", "optb": "144", "optc": "169", "optd": "25", "ans": "A", "explanation": "The numbers are squared in ascending order\nIn first circle,\n(3)2 = 9\n(4)2 = 16\n(5)2 = 25\n(6)2 = 36.\nIn second circle,\n(4)2 = 16\n(5)2 = 25\n(6)2 = 36\n(7)2 = 49.\nIn third circle,\n(6)2 = 36\n(7)2 = 49\n(8)2 = 64\n(9)2 = 81."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "8", "optb": "12", "optc": "16", "optd": "20", "ans": "C", "explanation": "(4 x 6) % 3 = 8\n(6 x 10) % 5 = 12\n(4 x 8) % 2 = 16."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "3", "optb": "5", "optc": "4", "optd": "6", "ans": "B", "explanation": "(7 x 3) + 8 = 29\n(4 x 3) + 7 = 19\n(5 x ?) + 6 = 31\n? = 5."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "94", "optb": "76", "optc": "16", "optd": "73", "ans": "A", "explanation": "(4)2 + (2)2 + (1)2 = 21\nand (5)2 + (3)2 + (8)2 = 98\nTherefore (6)2 + (7)2 + (3)2 = 94."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "75", "optb": "26", "optc": "25", "optd": "20", "ans": "B", "explanation": "(2)2 + (4)2 = 20\nand (3)2 + (9)2 = 90\nTherefore (1)2 + (5)2 = 26."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "18", "optb": "24", "optc": "36", "optd": "58", "ans": "B", "explanation": "(7 x 3) = 21 and (9 x 3) = 27\nand (4 x 9) = 36 and (2 x 9) = 18\nTherefore (9 x 6) = 54 and (4 x 6) = 24."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "60", "optb": "30", "optc": "20", "optd": "45", "ans": "B", "explanation": "(16 + 13) = (14 + 15)\nand (28 + 12) = (10 + 30)\nTherefore (29 + 16) = (15 + 30)."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "15", "optb": "19", "optc": "20", "optd": "18", "ans": "D", "explanation": "(3 x 4) + 3 = 15\nand (7 x 5) + 3 = 38\nTherefore (3 x 5) + 3 = 18."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "11", "optb": "14", "optc": "10", "optd": "12", "ans": "A", "explanation": "(15 - 12) + (10 - 9) = 4\n(28 - 12) + (16 - 20) = 12\nSimilarly, (23 -11) + (15- 16) = 11."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "25", "optb": "625", "optc": "125", "optd": "50", "ans": "C", "explanation": "All numbers are cubed,\n(7)3 = 343\n(1)3 = 1\n(3)3 = 27\nSimilarly, (5)3 = 125."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "9", "optb": "6", "optc": "15", "optd": "14", "ans": "B", "explanation": "(4 + 9 + 2) = (3 + 5 + 7) = (8 + 1 + 6)\nTotal in each case = 15."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "30", "optb": "13", "optc": "70", "optd": "118", "ans": "B", "explanation": "(15 + 12)/9 = 3\nand (44 + 28)/9 = 8\nTherefore, (64 + 53)/9 = 13."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "40", "optb": "38", "optc": "44", "optd": "39", "ans": "B", "explanation": "9 + (2)2 = 13\n13 + (3)2 = 22\n22 + (4)2 = 38."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "60", "optb": "46", "optc": "86", "optd": "75", "ans": "C", "explanation": "(30 - 24) x 8 = 48\nand (23 - 12) x 8 = 88\nTherefore, (92 - 86) x 8 = 48."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "5", "optb": "6", "optc": "8", "optd": "9", "ans": "D", "explanation": "93 - (27 + 3) = 63\n79 - (38 + 4) = 37\nTherefore, 67 - (16 + X) = 42\nX = 9"}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "3", "optb": "2", "optc": "7", "optd": "6", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Putting the position of the letters in reverse order\nP = 11, S = 8, V = 5 and Y = 2."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "9", "optb": "5", "optc": "7", "optd": "3", "ans": "A", "explanation": "5 x 8 x 10 = 400\nand 6 x 9 x 7 = 378\nTherefore 5 x 7 x ? = 315\n? = 9."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "8", "optb": "32", "optc": "4", "optd": "16", "ans": "C", "explanation": "(16)2 = 256\nTherefore, (2)2 = 4."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "1/2", "optb": "2/3", "optc": "3/4", "optd": "4/5", "ans": "D", "explanation": "From I row, 1 + (1/2) = 3/2\nFrom II row, 2 + (2/3) = 8/3\nFrom III row, 3 + ? = 19/5\n? = (19/5) - 3\n? = (4/5)."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "262", "optb": "622", "optc": "631", "optd": "824", "ans": "B", "explanation": "(915 - 364) = 551\n(789 - 543) = 246\n(863 - 241) = 622."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "12", "optb": "13", "optc": "11", "optd": "10", "ans": "C", "explanation": "(4 x 8) + 1 = 33\n(5 x 9) + 1 = 46\nSimilarly, (7 x 11) + 1 = 78."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "20", "optb": "26", "optc": "25", "optd": "75", "ans": "B", "explanation": "(2)2 + (4)2 = 20\n(3)2 + (9)2 = 90\nTherefore, (1)2 + (5)2 = 26."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "4", "optb": "6", "optc": "9", "optd": "8", "ans": "B", "explanation": "3 x 5 x 4 = 60\nand 5 x 7 x 4 = 140\nTherefore, 4 x 4 x ? = 96\n? = (96/16) = 6."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "2", "optb": "4", "optc": "6", "optd": "8", "ans": "C", "explanation": "(4 x 7) % 4 = 7\nand (6 x 2) % 3 = 4\nTherefore, (6 x 2) % 2 = 6."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "14", "optb": "22", "optc": "32", "optd": "320", "ans": "C", "explanation": "(5 x 6 x 4)/10 = 12\nand (6 x 7 x 5)/10 = 21\nTherefore (4 x 8 x 10)/10 = 32."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "18", "optb": "90", "optc": "108", "optd": "28", "ans": "C", "explanation": "13 + 15 = 28\n36 + 54 = 90\nTherefore, 45 + 63 = 108."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "8", "optb": "9", "optc": "10", "optd": "11", "ans": "D", "explanation": "(3 x 4 - 8) = 4\n(2 x 5 - 4) = 6\n(4 x 5 - 9) = 11."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "60", "optb": "50", "optc": "25", "optd": "21", "ans": "C", "explanation": ""}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "47", "optb": "45", "optc": "37", "optd": "35", "ans": "C", "explanation": "(3 x 3) + (5 x 6) = 39\nand (4 x 4) + (5 x 7) = 51\nTherefore, (3 x 4) + (5 x 5) = 37."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "A", "explanation": "(2)2 = 4\n(8)2 = 64\n(5)2 = 25\n(1)2 = 1."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "6", "optb": "7", "optc": "8", "optd": "9", "ans": "B", "explanation": "(10 + 9 + 14 + 7)/2 = 20\nand (11 + 16 + 10 + 13)/2 = 25\nTherefore, (15 + ? + 12 + 10)/2 = 22\nHence 37 + ? = 44\n? = 44 - 37\n? = 7."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "33", "optb": "38", "optc": "32", "optd": "37", "ans": "D", "explanation": "(5 x 6) + 2 = 32\n(7 x 6) + 2 = 44\n(7 x 5) + 2 = 37."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "6", "optb": "7", "optc": "8", "optd": "9", "ans": "A", "explanation": "(5 + 3)/2 = 4\nand (6 + 8)/2 = 7\nTherefore (8 + 4)/2 = 6."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "660", "optb": "670", "optc": "610", "optd": "690", "ans": "D", "explanation": "(1)2 + (5)2 + (4)2 + (3)2 = 51 x 10 = 510\nand (3)2 + (4)2 + (6)2 + (2)2 = 65 x 10 = 650\nSimilarly (0)2 + (1)2 + (2)2 + (8)2 = 69 x 10 = 690."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "18", "optb": "20", "optc": "21", "optd": "19", "ans": "B", "explanation": "1 + 2 + 3 + 4 = 10\nand 1 + 3 + 5 + 8 = 17\nSimilarly, 1 + 4 + 6 + 9 = 20."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "80", "optb": "114", "optc": "108", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "(4 + 8) x 9 = 108\n(5 + 4) x 12 = 108."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "8", "optb": "14", "optc": "10", "optd": "6", "ans": "C", "explanation": "For first triangle,\n10 - 4 = 6\n18 - 10 = 8\n18 - 4 = 14\nFor second triangle,\n14 - 8 = 6\n22 - 14 = 8\n22 - 8 = 14\nFor third triangle,\n11 - 5 = 6\n15 - 11 = 4\n15 - 5 = 10."}, {"question": "Which one will replace the question mark ?", "opta": "11", "optb": "19", "optc": "15", "optd": "22", "ans": "D", "explanation": "(2 x 2 - 1) = 3\nand (5 x 4 - 5) = 15\n(5 x 5 - 3) = 22."}]]}